Pictures didn't do any justice.
照片拍得多不真實啊
- I sense danger. - It's fine. I'm fine.
-我感覺到危險  -沒事兒 我很好
Were you car sick?
你暈車了嗎?
Of course I wasn't car sick.
我當然不是
That's why I ...
這就是我...
Richard, I'm not sure you fully understand
理查德 我不知道你知不知道
that you're walking into here, there are killness.
這裡有什麼 有血案
I know.
我知道的
I can handle this. Would you please, just give me some credit.
我能處理這個 求求你了 讓我消停一會兒吧
It's not gonna be quiet.
這是不會結束的
I'm having trouble believing how great this is.
你簡直無法相信這有多麼的棒
Are you coming?
你來不來呀
Oh, good Lord!
哦 我的上帝呀!
Claire?
克萊爾?
Oh, poor thing.
哦 可憐的小東西呀
At least it was quick.
幸好它死得快
It was a clean cut throat tear.
是被人割喉而死的
You should give him a proper burial.
你應該好好葬它
I feel just like I lost my parents.
我感覺像是死了親人一般
Oh, thanks.
啊 謝謝你
Oh, this is charming.
哦 這裡太好了
All the wire works. Good.
這個電線能用 挺好的
I do not know if the stove works.
我不知道這爐具能不能用
Maybe they have take-out menus.
也許這兒有外賣單
Oh, listen! Come here, come here. Come here
哦 聽! 快來 快來 快來
There she is. The moan of sea.
聽她 大海
Still in there.
聲音還在呢
Wow! Yeah.
哇 是呀
That's so...
這太
Oh, they got plenty of towels.
哦 這兒有好多毛巾呀
We didn't need to bring any.
早知道我們就不用帶了
Oh well ...
嗯
The fuse box is in the leaning closet, Richard.
保險絲盒在那個壁櫥裡面  理查德
Oh, star lights. Richard?
哦 還有星星燈 理查德?
The couch. It could be a problem.
那個沙發 它是個問題
Do not fix it.
不要管它
You're right.
你說的對
- Wonderful! Everything. - Good okay
- 非常好 一切都好   - 很好 嗯
You want to grab the luggage out of the car?
你把車上的行李拿下來好嗎?
I'll do it.
好吧 我去拿
Phil Turley is very concerned, Claire, about the community's efforts
克萊爾  菲爾·特裡非常關心
to protect the nesting ground.
社區是否有能力去保護鳥巢用地
So it should be.
我都說是這樣了
Listen, I put all my numbers
聽著 我把所有的號碼
on the top sheet of that memory pat by the telephone,
都放在電話旁邊最上面的備忘錄裡面了
so if you wanna tear that off and tape it off somewhere.
所以 你可以把它撕下來 貼在別的地方
I'm in surgery from nine until noon,
我從九點到中午要做手術
so I'll check you in after that. OK?
我手術之後再聯繫你 好吧?
Great. Good
好 很好
Are you sure you do not want rent a car?
你確定你不用租車嗎?
Didn't they say there was a bike?
難道他們沒有說過那有輛自行車嗎?
I think it's under the garage.
我感覺它在車庫裡呢
It's ten minutes to town. It's no big deal.
離城鎮只有十分鐘的車程 沒什麼大礙
Okay. It is up to you.
好吧 你說了算
So, what is your schedule look like for tomorrow?
那麼 你明天的行程是什麼?
I'll start at the very beginning.
我從頭開始
It is a very good place to start.
這樣最好開始
Speaking of which ...
哦 正好
Close your eyes.
把眼睛閉上
OK. Can open them.
好了 睜開吧
- Oh! - Marc just got one of these.
-哦!   -馬克剛弄到的
He said a five-year-old could use it.
他說就連五歲的孩子都會用
Richard, easy words.
理查德 小心用詞
Actually, I was thinking writing on the Corona.
事實是 我想用卡羅那打字
- Oh! - No, but this is good.
- 哦!     - 不是的 這樣很好
This is ...no, you're right. This is... This is better.
這 這 你是對的 這樣... 這樣更好
Okay.
好的
Richard? Easy to handle this
理查德?  應付得不錯嘛
Oh, I talked to Peter and Lucy
哦 我和彼得和 露絲商量過了
and they said they might come out the weekend the second.
他們說他們有可能週末來
Great, great!
好 好!
- Who? - Peter and Lucy?
- 誰來著?    -彼得和露絲?
Oh, good, yeah. They are always fun.
哦 對 想起來了 他們很好玩
Yeah, yeah.
對 對
You didn't bring... You didn't um... bring him out here, did you?
你不會... 你不會呃... 把他帶到這來吧?
What? No. No, of course not.
什麼? 不 不 當然不會
Okay.
好吧
All right
好的
Have a productive week, OK?
這週一定要高產(寫作)啊,加油哦?
Save some lives!
多救些生命!
R-No Pressure Love, C
理- 別太大壓力了  愛你的 克
- Any news? - Let go of me.
- 有什麼新消息嗎?   -放開我
Do you remember the time you and I we took a neighbor's bicycle
你記得那次我們倆拿了鄰家的自行車
a little fluph?
出了一點小意外不?
No, I do not. No. Will you let me go?
不 我不記得了 可以讓我走了嗎?
We both know that I'm not gonna quit the deal under these circumstances
你我都明白我不會停止的
until you prove otherwise I feel compelled to be on hands.
除非我覺得煩了
Can you step aside? I have things to do.
你可以讓開嗎? 我有事情要做
I sense danger.
我感覺到危險了
Would you stop saying that.
你別說了好不好
Be careful!
小心哦!
Aren't you a cheerleader, anyway?
你是個啦啦隊員吧?
I'm not.
我不是
You can so easy to be a cheerleader.
做個啦啦隊長也太容易了
You can so easily drop dead.
你去死也太容易了
Oh!
哦
No! No! Not like that.
不不 不是那樣的
Hands soap? Oh!
洗手液? 哦
No. It's for your wheels.
不是 是給你的車輪的
The squeak drives me nuts.
那個響聲讓我瘋了
It's a nice bike, though.
不過 這車不錯
Used to have one of these when I was young age.
我小時候也有一輛
So, how com you following me?
那麼 為什麼你跟著我?
I'm not.
我沒有呀
- Are to! - I'm not, I'm not.
- 現在就是啦!   -我沒有 我沒有
Are to! How come?
你有!  為什麼?
Well, I ...I kind of ur...  I just I moved in the town
嗯 我 我剛剛搬到這裡來
and I need ... uh ... a babysiter.
然後 我需要  呃... 一個保姆
I just thought you know maybe you ...you ...you uh might know somebody who
我在想 也許能你 你 你呃 認識誰...
Yeah Okay.
嗯 好的
When do you need me for?
你什麼時候需要我?
Oh!
哦!
Friday ...
週五
night ...
晚上
six ...
六點
Address and phone number?
你的地址和電話是多少?
18 Sag Harbor Road.
沙巴克港路 十八號
I don't know the phone number yet.
還沒有電話呢
Sorry.
不好意思
All right. I'll see you Friday.
那好 週五見
I'm Mr. .. I'm Richard.
我是... 我是理查德
Merton regarded his solitude as something sacred.
莫頓孤芳自賞
Merton regarded his solitude as something s...
莫頓孤芳自...
Face it. You can't live without me.
說吧 你不能沒有我
Do you mind?
別打擾我
I am communing with nature here.
我在和自然交流呢
Why are you so incapable of believing
你怎麼就不能相信
I can do things perfectly fine on my own?
我可以完完全全的自己搞定一切?
Becuse you never have.
因為你從來沒有成功過呀
Excuse me?
你說什麼?
Oh! Richard, Richard, Richard.
哦!  理查德 理查德 理查德
How many times, huh? How many times?
要我說多少遍? 啊? 說多少遍?
- I'm not gonna go through these ballet lessons alone. - Do not mock me.
- 我不敢一個人去芭蕾課! -別嘲笑我
I'm gonna like go through the college year, like, alone.
你連大學都不敢自己去
Okay, That
好吧 那個
You konw I do not need you, Captain.
長官 我不需要你 大哥
I'll resurrect my half-dead marriage alone.
我會利用我自己的力量挽救我那半死的婚姻的
Please, it's totally stupid!
你省省吧 蠢蛋!
I can't leave you to do it alone!
我不會讓你一個人的
Okay, good day, sir!
好的 祝你一天順利 先生
A good day!
萬事如意
Oh, my God!
哦 我的天呀
Merton regarded his solitude as something sacred.
莫頓孤芳自賞
Merton? Burton? Milton? Milton!
莫頓? 伯頓? 彌爾頓? 彌爾頓!
Milton regarded his solitude as something sacred.
彌爾頓孤芳自賞
Hey, sorry.
嗨 對不起
- I'm a little bit early.  - No no
- 我到的有一點點早    - 不 不
No problem.  Sorry, I ...I...
沒什麼 真抱歉 我 我
- I forgot your name. - Oh, that's okay.
- 我忘了你叫什麼了  - 哦 那沒什麼
I forgot yours' too.
我也忘了你的了
But I was thinking it was Paul, or Steve
但是 我記得是 波·斯蒂夫
or Dave ... maybe?
還是 戴夫  ?
- Richard.  - Oh, OK, that works.
- 是理查德  - 哦 好的 是這樣的
Oh, here!
哦 這個給你
It's ... uh ... it's a lovelot... for the kid
是 是個小熊... 給孩子的
Oh well ... actually ...
哦 那個 事實上
So, you just moved here?
那麼 你剛剛搬到這裡?
Where are you from?
你從哪兒來的?
Uh ... just ... just ...
嗯 從   從
- In the city. - Oh!
- 從城裡來的  - 哦
Yeah. It's only temporary.
對 但只是臨時的
My wife Claire is New York Presbyterian.
我妻子克萊爾是紐約長老會的一員
She's vascular surgeon.
她是個心血管外課手術醫生
Oh, wow!
哦 好厲害!
Is that her? She's cute.
是她嗎?  她好漂亮
Oh, yeah, that's the Doctor.
哦 對 那就是那個醫生
My parents went through sepration too, you know?
我父母也分開了
What? Oh, no, no no.
什麼?  哦 不 不 不
That is not what is happening here.
我們沒離婚
No, that's... no that's....
不是 那是... 不...  那是
No, isn't it?
不會吧?
Well, you should probably find out.
呃 你該自己想咯
Is it sleeping?
他睡了嗎?
Uh, the baby?
那個孩子?
Ah ...the thing about that baby.
啊 關於孩子的事
Are you thirsty?
你渴了嗎?
Oh, no.
沒
Look ... the baby ...the baby is not ... here.
看啊 孩子...  孩子不在... 這兒
What do you mean?
你什麼意思?
Basically, I guess ... uh ... There is no baby.
事實上 就是... 呃... ...  我沒有孩子
As such.
沒有
Is there no kid?
這兒沒有孩子?
Well ..
嗯
Sure then it will be easier.
那就會簡單一點了
So ...
那麼
When you think you will be home?
你什麼時候能到家?
Oh, nine ...  nine thirty?
哦 九點  九點半?
Okay, I got a lot of homework.
好吧 反正我也有很多作業要做
So ... have fun.
那...  玩的開心
OK.
好的
Chicken Shit!
雞屎
Gerhard dunn Renderer
傑哈爾·鄧 著色
richard dunn
理查德·鄧
Self-floating is a underrated form of psychological
自浮是一種維持平衡的
checks in balances.
一種形式
Never too high, never too low.
不高 也不低
Thought Mirton do it himself investigating in the rate of repeating breath work
莫爾頓通過觀察呼吸頻率來做到這點
Jesus.
上帝呀
- Don't say it. - Say what?
- 別說  - 說什麼?
- I know what you're thinking. - No. You don't
- 我知道你在想什麼  - 不 你不知道
I was thinking about pantaloons.
我想的不是事,是寂寞
- What are you doing? - You ass!
- 你在幹什麼?  - 你混蛋!
How did you get in here?
你是怎麼進來的?
The door was open.
門開著呢
What is extremely unsafe, by the way.
順便說一下 那是很危險的
You do not need to keep checking up on me.
你不需要老看著我
Is this the guy who was was following you?
是跟蹤你那個傢伙嗎?
Who does that?
誰在跟蹤你?
You do.I am just a babysitter.
是你 我只是來這做保姆的
Where is the child?
那孩子呢?
He dosen't have one child.
他沒有孩子
Abby, this guy is a pervert. We got to get out of here now.
艾比 這個人是個怪胎 我們馬上離開這兒
He is a famous writer, right?
他是個有名的作家 好吧?
Get a life?
他有自己的人生?
You're my life.
有你就是我的人生
You got a problem with me
你對我有意見嗎?
No. I don't get a problem with you.
不 對你沒什麼意見
And Bryce? - What about him?
那布萊斯呢? -他又怎麼了?
-He treats you like a shit.- When?
-你簡直不把他當人看 -什麼時候?
Always.  - No.
一直都是  -不
-Yes.  - Shut up.
-就是  -閉嘴
Oh, you're not.- not about what?
噢 你不是吧  -不是什麼?
What are you doing?- Making soup.
-你在幹嘛?  -熬湯
You've know this stocker guy for five minutes
你才認識這個跟蹤狂五分鐘
you're already making him soup?
就給他熬湯喝了?
I told you, Christopher,he is a writer.
我告訴你了克斯特佛 他是個作家
I love you.
我愛你
What are you doing out here?
你在這幹嘛呢?
I told her nine, nine thirty.
我跟她說九點或者九點半回去
No. I want to know what are you doing out here with the girl?
不 我是說 那女孩在家裡你跑出來幹什麼?
Nothing.
什麼也不做
It doesn't strick you as odd,somehow?
你不覺得這有點奇怪嗎?
A babysitter?
保姆?
I am under a lot of pressure, OK? I have to produce.
我壓力很大 知道嗎? 我得寫作
People expect literature.
人們想看好的文學作品
The doctor my publisher.I have got three months
那醫生 出版商 我只有三個月的時間
for three months create this thing.
三個月來完成這本書
The girl helped how?
這姑娘能幫上忙嗎?
Was I popular in high school?
我高中時受歡迎嗎?
In right respects?
在某些方面?
And the girl helps how?
這個姑娘到底能不能幫到你?
You have to question every decision I take?
你是不是要質疑我做的每個決定?
Make better decisions.
只是希望你作更好的決定
Just do the boys.
管好男的就行了
Oh! Oh, no! He needs me.
噢 噢 不! 他需要我
At the juncture, yeah.- juncture?
在關鍵時刻 確實  -關鍵時刻?
Yes.
沒錯
-oh  - just do it
-噢  -放手幹吧
When the world is in peril.
當這個世界面臨危險
When evil is around you.
當惡魔在你身邊
When danger is lurking.
當危險悄悄來臨
Who do you call?
你會喊出誰的名字?
Captain Excellent!
棒棒隊長!
I am a poster!
我就是傳奇!
There is something out there in the woods.
樹叢裡有些東西
Oh, my God!
噢 天哪!
The wolf?
是狼嗎?
Did not you hear?
你沒聽說嗎?
He escaped from the zoo this morning.
有狼今天早上從動物園裡逃出來了
There is a zoo here?
這裡有動物園?
no it's just...oh...
不是的 我只是...哦...
Whatever it is, I won't let it get you.
不管那是什麼 我都不會讓你有事的
Wanna soup?
想喝湯嗎?
What?
啥?
Yeah. I made soup.
嗯 我熬了湯
I thought that you maybe cold.
我覺得你可能會冷
What did you do tonight?
你今天晚上幹嘛了?
I went to the shore and did some thinking.
我去海邊思考些問題
For three hours? In freezing cold?
想了三個小時? 在這大冷天的?
You made this?
這是你做的?
Yeah
是的
-How?  - I do not know.
-怎麼做的?  -我也不清楚
A couple of carrots, and onion,one of your beers ...
放了點胡蘿蔔 洋蔥 還有一瓶啤酒
Oh, I hope that's OK. I just can't help myself
希望味道還好 我不好意思先試
No, it's fantastic.- You have not even tasted it yet.
不 這湯太棒了 -可你還沒喝呢
No, no. I mean, I mean ...
不 不 我是說 是說...
The fact of it... is fantastic that you made something
這件事本身...很棒 你什麼都不用
from nothing.
就能做出湯
Oh, you can ... you can ...you know
哦 你可以...你可以... 你知道
kind of make soup out of anything.
用任何東西做湯
That's the great thing about it.
這是做湯最大的好處了
just whatever left things around, you know
只要有東西在
you can take all the crap that's surrounding in your frige and
你可以把冰箱裡所有的東西拿出來
you can do it up that you can touch to the part you can make soup better
就可以慢慢學著把湯做好
I go with a soup.
我比較喜歡熬湯
Oh, it's superb!
哦 實在太好喝了!
Thank you.
謝謝
No.really!
真的!
It's... excellent.
這湯...美味無敵
Do you remember the moment that you realized
你還記得當你發現
the soup did not have to come out of a can?
湯不是從罐頭倒出來的感覺嗎?
you've got manufactured
你自己做
Your chicken noodles can kick Campbell  noodles' ass any day all week
你自己做的雞肉面比罐裝雞肉面好吃一千倍
I think I'm having that moment right now.
我覺得現在就有這種感覺
Plus, it is very nutritious which which is good.
還有 這個很有營養 不錯
What uh... what happened there?
呃... 這是怎麼回事?
Oh, sorry ... uh ...
噢 對不起... 呃...
It's just a boyfriend thing.
那是我男朋友
This bird kind of reminds me of him.
這鳥讓我想起他
He's chicken shit.
他就是個雞屎
Actually it's not a chicken.
實際上這並不是雞
It's a North America Heath Hen
這是北美黑琴雞
Relative of great perit chicken, but not technically a chicken.
是雞的親戚 但嚴格來講不算是雞
It's extinct now.
它現在已經滅絕了
The last few lived out here out of the nature preserve
最後的幾隻就住在這兒的自然保護區裡
I do not know that.
沒聽說過
I am not a birder or anything,
我不是個鳥類專家什麼的
it just the the last surviving heath hen is a character ...
但是這最後的幾隻倖存者是那裡面的重要角色
-in uh...   -In what?
-呃   -249A58C4里面?
This bird is the main character of this book ...you know
這些鳥兒是我正在創作的書的
I'm attempting to produce.
重要角色
Uh ... write...
哎...寫作...
Finish.
完了
Actually to start.
實際上是開始動筆
Saying it out loud, just sound kind of stupid.
說出來 好像很蠢
Well, there is... there's Chicken Little.
恩 相似的也有《小雞快跑》
You know, little red hen?
還有 《小紅雞》?
Henny Penny?- Yeah, exactly.
《小母雞潘妮》-是的 沒錯
Exactly.
沒錯
There are lots of books out there about um ...
還有很多書寫...
poetry.
詩的
We should settle up- Okay.
我們該結錢了 -好的
-Is that about right? - Actually ... uh ...
-這些夠嗎?  -實際上...恩...
I am twelve an hour.- Oh, okay.
一個小時十二塊  -哦 好吧
I only have a ten. Do you have change?
我有張十塊的 你有零錢找嗎?
Oh Let me check.
我看看
How come your boyfriend's a  chicken shit?
為什麼說你男朋友是雞屎呢?
Not my business, so ...
跟我無關 所以...
No.He just ...
不是 他只是...
He is a bug, you know, it's like when when he's with me he is all
他是個臭蟲 知道嗎 他跟我在一起時一個樣
you know when he's with friends he's all...
跟朋友在一起又是另一幅臉孔
whatever he's a fucking chicken shit
不管怎麼說 他就是該死的雞屎
-Right.  - Uh, okay, so ...
-好吧  -額 好吧 那麼...
-Thank you.  - Thank you.
-謝謝  -謝謝
Can I ask you a quick question?
能問你個問題嗎?
Sure.
當然
Is this couch make me look fat?
我坐在這個沙發上是不是特顯胖
I wouldn't sit there.
我不會坐那上面
So, okay, uh ...
所以說 好吧 哦...
Good luck with the chicken book .
祝你寫書順利
Same time next week?
下周還是這個時間?
Okay.
好吧
You didn't tell me your name.
你還沒告訴我你叫什麼名字
Richard?
理查德?
Are we separated?
我們分開了嗎?
What?
什麼?
Is this a trail of separation what are we doing?
我們現在做的事是做分開的試驗嗎?
What makes you think that?
你怎麼這麼想呢?
I do not know. Are we separating?
我也不知道 我們分開了嗎?
Sweetness, if we were in separating
親愛的 如果我們分開了
you'll be the first to know.
你一定是第一個知道的
I guess.
我想是的
Well we don't have to discuss.
我們沒必要說這些
Trust me.
相信我
Okay.
好的
Good
很好
It Just moved
它剛才動了
well, that is not possible. It's been boiled.
哦 這不可能 他已經被煮熟了
To death.
死了
Poor little Loui
可憐的小路易
Well don't name it, Richard.
別給他起名字 理查德
I mean ... do whatever you want.
我是說...你愛幹嘛幹嘛
No, don't don't name your food.
不 不包括給食物起名字
Here
來
Oh!
哦!
Here. Right?
來 好啦
Uhm? Go.
恩? 吃吧
Uhm?
嗯?
If only everything in the world could be coverd in butter,
如果世界上的說有東西都包裹上黃油
what world that will be?
那將會是一個什麼世界啊?
I guess.
我猜
What a buttery world .
多油膩的世界
He any good?
他有什麼好的?
I do not know. It's a kinka wordy.
不知道 這書有點嘮叨
So, what does the rendered world render?
那麼 被改變的世界怎麼樣?
I have not get that part yet.
我還沒看到那呢
Well, let me know.
好吧 到時告訴我
I'm sure there's something brilliant.
我肯定那很棒
What were you doing in my gym class?
你去我的體育課幹什麼?
Nothing.
沒什麼
You think I didn't see you?
你覺得我沒看到你嗎?
I was just there for more support.
我只是給你打打氣
-I am sick of volleyball. - you do not
-我排球打得爛極了 -並不是
-I'm sick of everything. - No,you don't.
-我什麼都做不好  -不 別這麼說
You're fantastic cross the blocker
你的球越過了攔網的 棒極了
Shut up.
閉嘴
-I never go out anymore.- You gonna leave,OK?
-我再也不想出去了-你得離開了 好嗎?
I'm meeting Bryce later.
我等會要見布萊斯
He's beneath you know.
他在下面 你知道的
Well you gonna lose some shit
你該減減肥了
It's freezing in here. Run the heater
這裡面冷死了 開暖氣
You want to pay for the gas?
你給油錢啊?
Are you done?
完了嗎?
Yeah
完了
See you later.
待會見
OK.
好了
Well just go for it - I'm going.
快開始夾吧 -我要開始了
Well, OK well he's dead now.why don't you go. Damn it. It's your turn.
哎 好吧 他死了 你來吧 該死的 到你了
I do not know how to do this all day. I mean, there's so much pressure.
真不知道你每天是怎麼做到的 壓力太大了
-That's just a game. - I know.
-那只是個遊戲  -我知道
Nobody dies here.
沒人會死
-Go ahead, please. - Can we play something else.
-你開始吧 拜託  -我沒還是玩點別的吧
No it's fine, you know.- Right.
不 沒關係 你知道的 -好的
Let's see.
看看
-Well, it was fun.- Yes, it was.
-真好玩啊 -是啊
Fantastic Weekend
週末過得很開心
Have a productive week and I will see you on the 15th .
這周好好創作 我們十五號見
Yes.
好的
What?
什麼?
Why are you standing?
你為什麼站起來了?
Oh!
噢!
-Really?  -Really.
-來真的?  -真的
Well, it's like that
嗯 就那樣
You don't want to stuck that dime out because it smells like you your mouth
你不會因為它像你口一樣臭就把它弄出來吧
The cowboy outfit for your 7th great book picture.
記得你第七本書封面的牛仔造型?
Remember? The horny tart? The huger strike?
牛角包? 絕食抗議?
Of course you're against those decisions.
當然你反對那些東西
Because if you didn't listen to me it's just fine
如果你不聽我說 也沒什麼
you were just a kid.
你那時只是個孩子
Now it's grow up time.
現在該長大了
Babysiter? Bad, Richard.
保姆? 太遜了 理查德
very, very bad, Richard.
太遜 遜呆了 理查德
The chairs can be a problem.
這些椅子會是個問題
Six. A lot
六張 好多的啊
Making the monkey
疊猴子
A humorous monkey is popular in the zoological garderns
有趣的猴子在動物園裡很受歡迎
For example:
例如:
It's lovely that you make a baby mokey
你可以疊用一小張紙
with a small paper
疊一隻小猴子
and you put it on the mother monkey.
放到媽媽猴子上面 很可愛的
Fold a top right corner.
折下右上角
Why origami? Why now?
為什麼玩起折紙? 現在?
I need something to do with my hands.
我得用手做點東西
I have the trouble in telling which is the monkey and which is the swan?
我還分不出哪只是猴子 哪只是天鵝呢
- Can't be all of them? - Oh, no.
-這裡還沒齊吧?  -噢 沒
There's much more on the truck.
車上多著呢
Oh, great. Start bring them in.
噢 好 搬進來吧
Horton ...
霍頓...
Richard, for the love of God, Do not do this, please.
理查德 看在上帝的份上 別去 拜託
Listen to me you're going to make a huge mistake
聽我說 你要犯下大錯了
You're going forward?
你要去是吧?
It's Abby... my name
艾比... 是我的名字
- Oh, you got rid of the couch. - Yeah, the couch was a problem.
-噢 你把沙發弄走了  -嗯 它是個問題
This is for you.
給你的
Oh! It's a ...
哦!是...
Let's see ...
看看...
It is a fish.
是條魚
A dead fish.
死魚
- Of all dead fish. - Yeah.
-一條死死的魚  -是啊
My dad fishes, make for a living
我爸釣魚的 生計來的
It is a fluke
是比目魚(也有幸運的意思)
In what sense?
怎麼幸運法?
It is called a fluke.
它就叫這個名字
The water around here, something like that
附近水域到處都是這種魚
So is eatable?
那它可以吃吧?
Yeah
對
A fluke is uh... that's great. Thanks.
比目魚啊... 太好了 謝謝
So I um I read that book you wrote
我 呃... 我看了你寫的書
I hope that's OK?
希望你別生氣?
Reading my book, of course.
看我的書 當然沒問題
You may be one of the few, but ...
很少人喜歡的 但是...
So you're out tonight? On the town?
你今晚要出去嗎? 去鎮裡?
I do not know.
我不知道
What the people of Montauk do on a Friday night you know
摩塔克 的人們星期五晚上喜歡幹嘛
The yards are totally dance.
他們喜歡去跳舞
So, you probably like that
你可能會喜歡吧
It's uh down by the harbour You can't not miss.
在海港旁邊 你會看到的
What did you think of the uh... ... the book?
你覺得呃... 這書怎麼樣?
I do not know. What do you think of it?
我不知道 你覺得呢?
Me? Oh I uh...  you know ... It's ...uh
我? 噢  我 呃... ... 就是... ... 呃
has got its strength ...
它有自己的優點...
got its moments ...
有自己的機會...
I hate it.
我討厭它
You should probably by that fish in the frige
你最好把那魚放冰箱裡
It's little stink of the whole house
不然它會熏到整個屋子的
Trust me, I know.
相信我 我瞭解
What?
什麼?
Soup ingredients .
湯料
You know, if you feel like it.
如果你喜歡的話
You bought me a turnip?
你還給我買了蕪菁
You're making it silly me.
你在作弄我啊
Well, I can sell if you don't feel like it
呃 如果你不喜歡我可以把它賣掉
No pressure.
別給自己壓力
Your book was cool actually
其實你的書很棒
Kind of blew me away
讓我很震撼
- Want uh... have something to eat? - Thanks no.
-呃... 想吃點東西嗎?  -謝謝 不了
I have got soup at home
我家裡有湯喝
Homemade
私房湯
Can be that
嗯 是那樣
- Another beer? - Sure.
-再來一杯?  -好的
-So uh...  What brings you down here? - A Book ... a bird.
-那... 你為什麼來這裡呢?  -書... 鳥
A book about a bird.
關於鳥的書
research book, you know
科研書
My wife makes a good chatter
我妻子嘮嘮叨叨
Not so much a claim chatter
不是講什麼大道理
I can expect more a corn chatter.
是嘮叨那些芝麻綠豆的
My Lorrain She can shock a dozen oysters in a minute and a half.
我羅利安 她可以在分半鍾內雷倒那些悶蛋
Local moppet oyster?
本地文靜的小姑娘?
That's the one
就是
My wife invented and patterned a life-saving
我妻子發明了並做了一個救人
polarimeter shunt.
極化分流器
- Song, you say? - Song.
-拿呢?  -分流器
So there is a heath hen
有只黑琴雞
hunker down the campion.
在草地裡蹲著
- Just down the road here.  - Yep.
-就在路邊吧  -對
As game warrent.
管理員
The Alfred guy.
那個艾爾佛雷德
Yeah it could at correct Alfred is the actual name
對 其實艾爾佛雷德是真名
In the book I'm going to call him Horton or ... Morton.
在書裡 我會叫他霍頓或者莫頓
Anyway, he's brought his flock of heath hens,
不管了 他把他那群黑琴雞
back from the brink of extinction.
從滅絕邊緣拯救回來了
Possible
有可能
I mean he was down to eleventh o'clock  I say eleven you know. But now with care
我是說 他打起十二分精神 再加上悉心照顧
and then I say a love and now he's got two hundred.
我會說是愛 現在 他現在有兩百隻了
- You konw it's like the hen is saved. - Sage, Thank God.
-就是這雞安全了  -聖人啊 感謝上帝
But because the story is a tragedy,
但故事是個杯具
You know what happen?
你知道後來發生什麼事嗎?
- What? - Fire.
-什麼?  -火災
- No Come on!  - Yes, it sweeps accross preserved.
-不 得了吧! -就是 火橫掃保護區
Of course the heath hens are not nature's most intelligent bird to begin with.
當然 黑琴雞不是自然界最聰明的動物
They are just sitting there you know... They never sense to run or fly
它們就坐在那... 它們都不會跑 不會飛
while You know, when the fire runs out there're just five birds remained.
到了 到了火滅了以後 只剩五隻了
Roast chickens.
燒雞
What happens to the five?
那五隻後來怎樣了?
They dwindle you know they dwindle
慢慢減少 慢慢地
till there's just one left you know
最後只剩一隻了
Just one... this one poor...  stupid little thing, you know, just a stupid bird... just one
就一隻... 這可憐的... 蠢傢伙 笨死了 就一隻
It is a true story
這是真實故事
Go to hunt for my friend here, Mike.
我去找我朋友 麥克
Chicken shit.
雞屎
Oh, you did make soup. Bless your heart!
噢 你真的做了湯 謝謝
Just a small act of great kindness, but I can't tell you
只是小小的心意 但我無法形容
what it means to me.
它對我的意義
Well, it's no big deal. It's just a soup
嗯 沒什麼 湯而已
You are such a beautiful girl
你真漂亮
You are such a beautiful child
你這孩子真漂亮
- You're loaded - No, no ... I well, yes.
-你喝大了  -不 不 不... 我... 是的
Okay, I s hould go. As you're today a little longer...
好了我得走了因為你今天出去時間長了...
No you know what I am I'll tell you who I am.
不 等等 我告訴你我是誰
Just in case you are interested.
你可能會感興趣
- This is who I am. - What?
-這就是我  -什麼?
I am the only child of only child the only child.
我是九代單傳的單傳的單傳
You know what that means?
你明白是什麼意思吧?
No cousins?
沒兄弟姐妹
It means I am the end of bloodline
我就是最後一點血脈
The last of my kind.
最後一個
OK, well, then have some kids
好的 那就生些小孩吧
Said the babysiter
保姆這麼說
Ahh, if you want to know how...
啊 如果你想知道怎樣...
You look it's going to be 60 bucks Ok? You should go to bed
看 你該給我六十塊 好吧? 你該去睡覺
I do not blame her the doctor You know, she is ... just ...
我不是怪那醫生 她... 只是
She's a human mechanics.
她是個人肉機器
She's got her hands inside human beings
她把手申到人類身體裡去
every day ... is a machine to her, you know.
每天都這樣... 她跟機器沒區別
She's a machine doesn't break.
永遠不會停下來
like a rock factory
像碎石機那樣
So how are you going to creat life for you know it's gonna to end up and down
你怎麼創造生活呢 你都知道會有高低起伏了
I mean I get it... I get it!
我是說 我知道... ... 我知道!
I don't blame her, but ...
我不是怪她 但是...
Hey, I'm sorry.
嘿 對不起
Yeah... it's she
嗯 她就這樣
She does not realize that Human beings are warm.
她根本不知道人類是暖的
You know They need contact
他們需要接觸
They need warmth ...I mean
他們需要溫暖... 我是說
You are such a beautiful girl. You are such a beautiful child.
你真漂亮 你這孩子真漂亮
No, no, no!
不 不 不
Shit! I mean to go
操!我要走了
-Why all men so sticks?  -It's me?
-天下烏鴉一樣黑  -說我嗎?
I just said he is lonely
我是說他很孤獨
We are all lonely.
我們都很孤獨
- May be I shouldn't have hit him . - No, you definely should have
-也許我不該打他  -不 當然要打
Okay, would you rather?
好吧 你覺得呢?
I don't know
我不知道
Oh, come on
哦 來吧
Would you rather have no TV for a year?
你願意一年不看電視
or just be able to wacth the golf channel?
還是只能看高爾夫台?
-Golf channel - Yeah me too.
-高爾夫台  -嗯 我也是
At least have the TV.
至少能看一下
Your turn.
到你了
OK
好
Would you rather have no freinds or no parents?
你想沒朋友還是沒父母?
Claire?
克萊爾?
Richard, the couch is outside
理查德 沙發在外面呢
It is the 15th already?
今天到15號了嗎?
-Are you OK? -Yes I am
-你還好嗎?  -好啊
There's soup in the kitch. Have you been making soup?
在廚房裡有湯 你會煮湯嗎?
I'll be right back
等等我
All right. You made the soup. What baby sitter?
好的 你做的湯 什麼保姆?
Work is going great while I'm still not here?
我不在寫作進行得不錯吧?
Drink it up Great Get out there
灌下去 好 出去
You know a funny thing about soup?
你知道湯這玩意嘛?
You get the ingredients basicall into the pot
你把材料都放到鍋裡
along with the sauce and the ur... that stuff and the ur... juice
再加進湯 呃... ... 就是... ... 汁
-You mean the broth?  -Right... and then...
-你是說湯底?  -對... 然後呃...
just needs some cooking
再煮一下就搞定了
Richard is anything wrong?
理查德 發生什麼事了嗎?
I'm not... I'm concerned
我不是... 我只是 擔心
Oh, well thank you for your concern, Claire.
噢 謝謝你的關心 克萊爾
Speaking of how are your patients?
說回來 你的病人都怎樣?
Are they doing well?
他們恢復得挺好的吧?
And what's some of their names?
他們都叫什麼名字?
No you've got a bruise right here
不 你這裡有淤青
Oh well you know... beaten well my life you know...
哦 呃... 被生活打倒了...
Winds of change.
風水輪流轉啊
Anyway I want to do unloading of boxes
不管了 我想把盒子的東西搬出來
If you don't want to have a pitch in so you would then grab some brunch
如果你不幫忙的話 你做午餐好吧
Oh, no, Richard. Are these all?
哦 不 理查德 全在這裡嗎?
Oh, yes.
噢 是啊
Why? Why would you do that to yourself?
為什麼? 為什麼要這樣?
Well, I'm emarking on writing of my second life
呃 我正要寫我的第二人生
much anticipated second novel It should be the reminder of the remarkable
就是第二本小說 來紀念我第一本小說
I mean quite noble failure of my first novel didn't sell any copies  whatsoeve
失敗 沒賣出去
Richard, I can't go down the throat with you
理查德 我不能幫你了
Oh, no, no, no. It's going to be rather motivational really
噢 沒事沒事 能幫就幫才好
- That was smooth - Hey, I got to proven
-一切順利啊  -嘿 我有證據
- Wait, wait, wait. - What?
-等等等等  -什麼?
My super-senses are telling me something.
我的直覺告訴我
What?
什麼?
Yes,I think the Dr.may be on to you.
我猜她已經覺得你不對勁了
Shut your mouth up.
給我閉嘴!
Knock, knock. Who's that?
咚咚咚 是誰?
Shit! What do you want?
該死! 你想幹什麼?
I came to see if you are OK.
我來看你是否還好
- Because your head was a...- It's fine, I'm fine.
-因為你的頭... - 沒事了 我很好
You need to go now.
你現在就得走
What?
什麼?
Screw you too.
你也滾吧
And you were the one who came up to me
是你先靠近我的
by the way.
順便提醒你
What?
什麼?
Last night.
昨晚
Asshole. I just wanted to apologize.
混蛋 我只是來向你道歉
For hitting you, but forget it, creep.
我打了你 但算了吧 小氣鬼
Wait! Abby
等等! 艾比
The Dr.'s out of shower. And voila.
醫生從浴室出來了 你看
- Richard, who was that? - Girl scout.
-理查德 是誰呀? -女童軍
Girl scout.
女童軍
Oh, okay.
哦 知道了
Horton regarded his solitude as something sacred.
霍頓孤芳自賞
Horton? Norton? Norwood? Norwood!
霍頓? 諾頓? 諾伍德? 諾伍德!
Norwood regarded his solitude ... Oh!
諾伍德 孤芳...哦!
How's it coming?
進展如何了?
Norwood regarded his solitude as something ...
諾伍德孤芳自...
Richard, what's this?
理查德這是什麼?
The fluke.
比目魚(有幸運的意思)
-In what way? - The fish is called a fluke.
-怎麼幸運法? -這種魚叫這個名字
The water around here is swimming with them.
附近水域到處都是這種魚
Oh! And what are we planning on doing with it?
哦! 那我們拿這怎麼樣?
I have to have a plan,
我一定要有個計劃
can I just have a fish in the house?
而不能只是買回家一條魚嗎?
Yes, fine.I 'm Sorry.
是的 好吧 對不起
I thought we could cook it.
我想我們應該把他弄熟
And then eat it.How was that?
吃了它 怎麼樣?
I guess i just hadn't caught up with the fact that you are a cook now.
我想我還沒適應你已經會自己做菜了
Okay, stop, stop it,
行了 停! 停下!
you could stop it, please.Stop now.
求你 你可以停下了! 快停下!
Stop, stop it, stop please!
停 等會 請等一下!
Stop!
停!
Abby!
艾比!
Who the hell is that?
見鬼 那是誰?
I don't think i got a chance to pay you the other night.
我想我還沒來得及給你那晚的酬勞
- How...is sixty. - Keep it.
-多少...六十 -省省吧
You don't even have a kid, so ...
你根本沒有孩子 所以..
I think there was a kind of misunderstanding or something about my actions,
我想你對我的行為有些誤會
my intentions, pretty sure, sense or something.
還有我的動機 想法之類的
Whatever. I'm sure you're sorry to it,so let so.
隨便吧 我知道你很內疚 那就行了
I'm not sorry, actually about all that.
其實我不是為那個道歉
I'm sorry about that I was so abrupt at the
我抱歉 因為那天對你很粗魯
- House ...- Your wife was there.
- 在家門口 -你妻子在家
- Yeah, I figured that out.- Yes.
-對 我知道了 -是的
- It would be awkward, you know?  - No, actually I don't know.
-那會很尷尬 你知道的  -不 我不知道
Well, Claire wouldn't really understand our ...
克萊爾不會真正理解我們的...
Our what?
我們的什麼?
Our friendship.
我們的友情
Abby!
艾比!
Come on! We're out here.
快點! 我們要走了
Anyway, I want to let you knew I respect you.
不管怎樣 我想讓你知道我是尊重你的
Is that the chickenshit?
這就是那陀鳥屎嗎?
- Yeah - It's a good-looking guy.
-是的 -長得挺不錯
Yeah, he sure think so.
對啊 他肯定也這麼覺得
Are you coming or what?  We gonna to Texas.
你要不要來了? 我們要去德克薩斯
- Yeah,Just a minute. - I'm Richard.
-是的 等會兒 -我是理查德
Look, you said you wanna hanging out when you were not out.
嘿 在家裡是你說要出來溜達的
It's Okay, Abby.I don't wanna keep you from a new day
沒關係 艾比 我不會耽誤你一整天的
Who's your friend with bike?
你這騎單車的朋友是誰?
Abby has been babysitting for me. How's Wednesday night?
艾比為我照看孩子 週三晚上怎麼樣?
Sure.
當然可以
Damn, girl! Move your ass!
該死 丫頭 快點!
Sorry.
對不起
He was following you here?
他跟蹤你?
Richard?
理查德?
- Richard, are you here? - I'll be right there.
-理查德 你在嗎? -我就來了
Do not.
別去!
Hey.How are you doing?
嘿 你好嗎?
- Come on, I wanna show you something.- Great! Okay.
-來吧 我帶你去個地方 -太好了!
I have a problem with my hands.
我的手出毛病了
What do you mean?
什麼意思?
They won't do what I want them to do.
他們不聽我使喚
What do you want them to do?
你想讓他們做什麼?
Anything. I do not know.
任何事 我不知道
Something useful.
一些有意義的事
I want them to build something or ...
我想讓他們去創造一些或者...
make something.
製造一些什麼
Like what?
比如?
Even Jesus, I mean if he was a carpenter.
即使耶穌 我是說如果他是個木匠
It was not enough to save mankind
那也不足以拯救人類
he needed a tray.
他也需要原材料
I am a flimsy man and insubstancial.
我是個脆弱的人 毫無存在感
Well, compared to Jesus ...
那只是和耶穌比起來
- I am a paper man.- No, you're a writer.
-我是個紙人 - 不 你是個作家
- Yeah, that's crucial. - Yeah, it is.
- 對 說的沒錯  -對 沒錯
Here we are.
我們到了
Where?
到哪了?
It is possible, so is sea
也許 大海也一樣
life and land with certain decries,
生命和土地一旦被反對
quietly was never see other again
此生就無法再次相會
Did I write that? I wrote that.
我寫過那個嗎? 我寫的
Hold this.
拿著這個
Abby?
艾比?
Come on!
別這樣!
Jesus!What are you doing?
天啊!你在幹什麼?
What are you doing?
你想幹什麼?
You can not do this.
你不能這麼做
Can't do that.
不能這樣做
It was me that daren't going.
是我不敢下水
It was really cold.
那天真的很冷
It was much, much colder than today, but ...
比今天要冷得多 但是...
You know, she wasn't gonna turn down the dare.
你知道 她不想退縮
You will like that
你會那樣的
And I woudln't be neither adventuress, so...
我也不想當什麼女冒險家 所以...
I do not know why she went in.
我不知道她為什麼也跳進水裡
In her cloths. ..
穿著衣服
I guess it maybe sort of warmer.
我想可能那樣更暖和
And she was laughing.
她在笑
And you know.
你知不知道
Fine.
好
And she was..Um...
然後她就...唔...
And she was calm.
她很平靜
Just under
一直往下沉
and gone and. ..
再沒回來...
I just stood there.
我就站在那裡
And in a couple of hours my mom came.
幾個小時之後 媽媽來了
And found me and I guess, you know.
找到了我 我想 嗯..
as waiting for her to swim back in, but ...
我正在等她游回來 但是...
she never did.
她再也沒回來
How old?
她多大?
Same just with me.
和我一樣大
We were twins.
我們是雙胞胎
Oh! Oh, my God!
噢! 噢 天啊!
That was a long time ago.
那是很久以前的事了
I'd like to go out there every year. Swim back to shore.
我每年都回去那裡 游回岸上
You know, I like to feel the cold.
我喜歡感受那種冷
You must have...I don't know what to say.
你肯定...我不知道該說些什麼
So we were both only children.
所以我們都只是孩子
That was our fate.
那是我們的宿命
Every year, and you knew it.
每年 你都知道
And you take that guy out there.
可你把那個人帶去
On this day.
就在這個日子
He didn't even know her.
他甚至都不認識她
I know.
我知道
Remember when I was the only one who talked to you?
記得以前只有我才和你講話嗎?
For a long time.
聊的很久
I know, but ...
我記得 但是...
He doesn't love you.
他並不愛你
That's your think you're wrong.
你的想法是錯的
What do you want me to say?
你想我說什麼?
I gotta some move to California.
我可能要去加利福尼亞一段時間
Shouldn't just assume my always being around
你不能以為我會一直陪在你身邊
because one day ... Maybe I won't.
因為某天...也許我不會了...
God! Stop it.
天吶! 別說了!
Is this what you want?
那就是你想要的嗎?
I don't have much history, do I?
我沒什麼故事可說 是吧?
That is relative visible.
的確有影響
Exactly.
一點不錯
Other people seem to have revise.
別人的生活都有改觀
Things happen to them.
他們人生經歷豐富
Life all turn in occurrences.
生命充滿各種傳奇色彩
I used to do things.
我也曾經有所作為
-Remember? -This is not about you.
-還記得嗎? - 跟你無關
Amazing things.
奇妙的經歷
What do you want me to say?
那你想要我說什麼?
I don't know.
我不知道
No, no. Tell me what you want me to say literally,
別 別 告訴我你想要我談些什麼?
because frankly poorly I got nothing.
因為我完全不知道該說什麼
Come here.
過來
But you have to touch civilizers,
但你必須去接觸人情世故
Richard,through your work
理查德 就你的工作來看
thought about your happiness be the happiness you brought to her biz.
你讓她不快 所以你才不快樂
Hey,um,look!
嘿 呃 是這樣
It's the fundraiser for the children in hospital tomorrow night
明晚有個為患病兒童的募捐活動
and I am thinking of donating
我想把那瓶1971年的
that bottle of wine, the 1971 Chateau Petrus .
波得路堡葡萄酒捐出去
I know I was saving up for a special occasion,
我知道我們在省錢以備不測
but what for that cost? So ...What do you think?
但是那能算什麼? 所以...你覺得如何?
Richard, did you drink that wine?
理查德 你把酒喝了?
That five-thousand-dollar bottle of wine
那瓶值5,000元的酒
It's not the raft. It was for the children.
也不是很貴 都是為了孩子
Will you can call me, please?
回我電話 好嗎?
Come in!
進來!
- Wow, check out the couch!- Yeah,You like it?
-喔 看看這個沙發! -沒錯 喜歡嗎?
- I made it with these.- Alright!
-我用這雙手做的! -真不錯!
- That's awesome!- Yeah, sit, sit, sit.
-太棒了! -對啊 坐 坐 坐
It's nice.
太棒了!
Oh, the ideas for titles.
哦 我想了一些書名
For your new book?
給新書的?
Cool, what do you got?
酷 你都想到哪些了?
Cloud escape. Death and Desolation.
烏雲消散   死亡和荒蕪
Daffodil. Memoirs of an Amnestic.
水僊花  失憶者的回憶錄
- Bolero  - Bolero?
- 波列羅舞 - 波列羅舞?
Okay.
好吧
Ad nauseum?
令人作嘔?
Almost Silence.
沒一個認同的
No?
沒有?
Pictures of a Blackberry Wine.
黑莓酒的肖像
Let's forget it.Titles are impossible.
哦 算了 標題是很難應付的
Paper Man.
紙人
You seem a lot more interesting than me.
你好像比我更有興趣
I'm not.
沒有
Just seems like that way because I have a dead sister.
只是我有個死去的姐姐
- Where have you been all day? - I do not know.
-你一整天都去哪兒了? -無可奉告
well.
哦
So the party in office this weekend failed
正籌辦的週末的派隊被擱置了
because of them.
都怪他們
- And what about the cove? - It's fucking cold out there.
-在那個山洞裡怎麼樣? -那兒凍死了
Big deal to find some place off.
那可真不好找別的地方了
What kind of party?
什麼樣的聚會?
What kind of party? Fucking party.
什麼樣的聚會?胡鬧的聚會
It's nothing, just friends hanging out.
沒什麼 一些朋友聚著玩玩而已
You can use my house.
你們可以在我家舉行
What?
什麼?
- Seriously?- Yeah. Why not?
-真的? -當然 為什麼不可以?
This weekend is not so good,because my wife's back, but
這周恐怕不行 因為我的妻子要回來
you know we can do next week. Friday?
但是下周可以 週五?
Friday is cool.
週五好啊
- Really?  - Yeah.
-真的麼? -是的
- I'll get a cake. - nice ... cool.
-我會弄一個蛋糕 -很好... ... 太棒了
What else guys need?
大家還需要什麼?
Appetisers,you know paper plates,these staff?
開胃菜 紙碟 之類的?
No, no, no. We're ok. We have coverage.
不 不 不 我們都有 我們準備這些
Great. We're on
太棒了 就這麼定了
Okay, thanks, man.
好的 謝謝 夥計
- You didn't have to do that.  - It'll be fun.
-你不必非舉行那個聚會的   -挺好玩的
Richard?
理查德?
Richard, please?
理查德 在麼?
Hi
嗨
When the world is in peril.
當世界面臨危險
When evil is around you.
惡魔在你身邊
When danger ...
當危險... ...
OK?
怎麼了?
- Richard, help me.  - You don't like it?
-理查德 幫幫我   -你不喜歡這樣麼?
All furniture is outside and. ..
傢俱全在外面
What the hell is this?
這他媽的都是什麼東西?
You seem disappointed, you're going up with your body language.
你的手勢可以看出來貌似你很失望
You don't pick up the phone once this week.
這周你一次電話都沒接
You don't
你一個電話
Call me once.
都不打給我
I traveled all the way out here and there's this!
我一路趕過來就看到這個!
Richard, say something.
理查德 給我個解釋
Well, I ...
嗯 我... ...
- What is it?  - What is what?
-這是什麼?  -什麼是什麼?
This? Whose is it?
這個 這是誰的?
Richard, just tell her.
理查德 告訴她
- Claire? - Yes?
- 克萊爾?  -怎麼了?
Are we unhappy or are we just pretendding to be unhappy?
我們是真的不快樂還是只是裝作不快樂?
What do you mean?
你什麼意思?
Are we just pretending to be unhappy,
我們只是為了給生活加點味道
to add dramaes to our life?
才裝作不高興嗎?
So that we seem somehow more substantial?
這樣會讓我們覺得實在點嗎?
I mean, think about it:
我的意思是 試想:
Our lives are embarrassingly easy.
我們的生活並不窘迫
We got plenty of money.
我們有充裕的錢
We got friends.
我們有朋友
Well, you got friends.
嗯 你有朋友
There are people out there who have real problems.
世界上窘迫的人多的是
You know?
你知道麼?
Real reasons to be unhappy.
的的確確有原因令他們不快樂
I mean I could be a coal miner dying of black loan , or something.
我是說我可能是個還不起債 或者什麼的礦工
You could be a Cincinnati clack on foodstuff
或者是西西那提街頭買個菜都砍半天價的
-What?  - I do not know.
-什麼?  -我不知道
I'm just on it. Doesn't it feel like we were faking it
我只是覺得 我們不在讓生活變得虛假
our unhappiness?
不開心都是裝出來的嗎?
No.
不
No. It's real.
不 是真的
It is very real.
很真
I'm going home now.
我要回家了
I think you think this's still charming.
我認為你覺得這生活很好
We aren't 23 any more.
我們不是小孩子了
You need to pull it together.
你要好好想清楚
Pick up the phone this week.
這周記著接電話
And bring the fucking furniture into the lawn!
把該死的傢俱搬到草地上
Norwood believes his solitude something like ...
諾伍德孤芳自... ...
Norwood? Norman? Richmond? Richmond!
諾伍德? 諾曼? 理查曼? 理查曼!
Richmond regarded his solitude as something like ...
理查漫孤芳自... ...
- Richmond?- Richmond.
- 理查漫?- 理查漫.
Schimithmond? Schimithmond!
斯密斯曼? 斯密斯曼!
Richmond regarded his solitude as something like ...
理查漫孤芳自... ...
Oh!
噢
Unbearable!
受不了啦!
Richmond regarded his solitude as something like ...
理查漫孤芳自... ...
Richmond regarded his solitude as something... unbearable.
理查漫孤芳... 忍無可忍
Scalpel.
刀
You started too high.You need to go down
你劃的太高了 你應該從頭的根部的下面
to the base of the head and cut off it, good.
開始切斷它 很好
Careful, careful, careful.
小心 小心 小心
Let me help you.
讓我來幫你吧
All right.
好的
Good, good, good.
不錯 不錯 不錯
OK.Would you rather ...
好的 你寧願後退
always walk backwards or being stabbed when take a new step?
還是等你敢才走下一步?
Why would I wanna do neither?
我可以兩個都不選麼?
It's a game, just pick one.
是個測試 選一個吧
Oh, throw in the pan. Beautiful!
哦 快放鍋裡 太棒了!
You are really good at this.
你還挺擅長這個呢
My wife reattach the leg today.
我妻子今天教了我一點
-Oh no  -You should be a fish monger.
-噢 不是吧   -你應該做個魚販
You know, monger some fish.
你知道 賣魚
Which one do you prefer,walking back
你選哪個?後退
or just step out?
還是邁出新的一步?
Could I just were a special kind of shoes or ...
我能穿有超能力的鞋或者... ...
No.
不可以
You look back in a minute. Gently gently gently
轉過去 輕點 輕點 輕點
I guess I would uh...  walk backwards,
我猜我可能會後退
I'm not good with pain. You?
我不喜歡受傷的感覺 你呢?
I like to see where I'm going.
我喜歡探索前方的路
OK. Come here.
好了 快過來
We'll hold this out.
我們拉開這個
- Oh,paper men.  - ou know, for your book.
-哦 紙人 -為你的書做的
Oh, yeah, yeah. I get something for you too.
哦 是的 是的 我也給你準備了點兒東西
Yeah. Close your eyes.
嗯 閉上眼睛
Oh!
哦!
A camel?
駱駝?
A peacock?
孔雀?
It's the swan.The beautiful and graceful swan.
是只天鵝 美麗又優雅的天鵝
Sorry.
不好意思
Oh!
哦!
Come in.
請進
- We look good.- Yeah.
-看起來不錯吧 -嗯
Wow, you really went out loud.
哇 你真是太給力啦
Yeah.too much?
嗯 誇張麼?
No.
不
No.It looks great.
不 看起來很棒
The party's house.
晚會都已經準備好了
Barrels are here and I got the uh... put in order in the kitchen.
酒桶在這邊放著並且那邊廚房擺好了開胃菜
I think it will flow all that way.
我覺得這樣擺放順一點
Oh, this is a pita?
哦 這是個皮偶麼?
Yeah, I've one for the donkey you know go classic.
嗯 我做的有點蠢 很經典吧
You don't like parties much, do you?
你不太喜歡聚會 對麼?
No. I get a little nervous.
不 我有點兒緊張
Oh, relax. It'll be fun.
哦 放鬆點 會很有趣的
Okay.
好的
No!
不會吧!
- Hey.- Hey.
-嗨 -嗨
- Shit. - I know.
-操  -我知道
- Where is the frige?- Do not play the asshole.
-冰箱在哪? -別耍混蛋了
- Whats up? - Whats up,man!
-怎麼了?-怎麼了 哥們兒!
- Where do I put this?- Kitchen.
-這個放哪兒? -放廚房
- How about the box?- Wherever, man.
-箱子麼? -放哪兒都行 老兄
Wherever you feel is right
只要覺得合適的地方就行
- Is my castle? - What?
- 這是我的城堡?-什麼?
Right.
好吧
Where are the cups.
杯子在哪兒?
Hey!
嗨!
Welcome to party central.
歡迎來參加聚會
Go over here.
隨便玩
Hey! Hey!
嗨!嗨!
How great the guy is he.
這人太好了
No body wants the party
我以為沒人來呢
What's up Come, come.
怎麼回事 快來 快來
Today is my day!
今天是我的得意日!
Hey.
嗨
Tim-tim!
碰碰!
High School for me was a time of self-discovery.
高中生活對我來說就是發現自我的過程
When I look back I'm dull.
想想以前 我真蠢
Got a sick You would not want to be 17 years again, uhm?
真噁心 你不想再回到十七歲了 對吧?
We are 15.
我們十五歲
Oh! Sorry.
哦!不好意思
- Do you mind? - What are you doing?
-不好意思? -你他媽在幹什麼呢?
- What?- What the fuck are you doing?
-什麼? -你他媽的在幹什麼?
What about Abby?
艾比怎麼辦?
Goodbye, Abby.
再見艾比
You do this to her You don't do this to the little girl
你搞她好了 你別搞那小女孩
Mind your own business,you pervert.
別管閒事 變態
Chicken shit.
雞屎
-What do you call me? - Chicken shit bastard.
-在叫我麼?-雞屎小混蛋
Can not talk to me like that.
不准你這樣跟我說話
You do not talk to me like that,you fucking weired
你不能這麼跟我說話 草泥馬
You think you can thread me you a child.
你以為我怕你這個屁孩麼
I'm a child, huh? That's what I am
我是個屁孩 哈?我就是屁孩
Leave him alone! What are you doing?
別碰他!你在幹什麼?
Stop it!
住手!
- Are you okay?  - What is the deal?
-你沒事吧? -怎麼回事?
What is the deal? You fucked with him?
怎麼回事?你和他胡搞了?
- Stop! - You fucked with her?
-住口!-你和她胡搞了?
No!
沒有!
I do not give a shit.
我操才不管
You can have her.She is fucking crazy anyway.
你可以要她 她也他媽的瘋
Why don't you go back to loony bin
你怎麼不回你的
where you belong.
瘋人院去
And take him with you!
把他帶上!
Get the fuck out!
滾蛋!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
好 好 好
Get fuck out! Now! Go!
他媽的滾蛋!快! 滾!
What are you looking at? Go out here!
操你媽看什麼看?滾出去!
Party is over.
聚會完了
Chicken shit.
雞屎
He is an asshole.
他是個混蛋
Yeah
是的
Great party?
聚會很棒吧?
Yeah.
嗯
I love you.
我愛你
What?
什麼?
I think .. uh ... in an appropriate way.
嗯... 呃... 一個合適的方式
I  I thing you should know.
我覺得你該知道
I discovered I just find when I examined
我發現我審視
my heart, I found ...
自己的內心時 我發現...
I think there's love there.
我覺得心裡有愛
For you.
是對你的愛
Yeah.
的確是
I love you.
我愛你
it wasn't... it wasn't really of love only being in use.
不是... 不是只有愛這個詞兒
I mean, as lonely as ever, I called on months
我是說 我曾經很孤獨
you know just until I ...
大喊大叫了幾個月直到我...
My parents thought of ...
我父母以為...
I don't know.
我不知道
I never told them.
我從來沒告訴過他們這些
Never ...
從來也沒有
told anyone else.
告訴其他任何人
That was a pact.
那是個約定
me and Amy were both there to go.
我和艾米都會去
enter the water and she didn't...
下水去 可她沒有
didn't swim back.
沒有游回岸上
I swam back.
我游回來了
I could ...I could...
我應該能...我應該能...
I do not know what we were so unhappy about. I mean ...
我不知道什麼使我們如此不開心 我是說
How could we be so unhappy about ...
我們怎麼能這麼不開心
I think you ...you are too young to know
我想 你還太小
you can get over anything.
不知道你能跨過很多所謂的坎兒
He's always made poor decisions.
他總是做出錯誤的決定
same with her.
她也是
I feel helpless.
我真感到無助
How long have you been with her?
你陪她多久了?
Since she was 8.
從她八歲的時候
You?
你呢?
Oh, Christ, it's got to be over 40 years.
天啊 都有四十多年了
second grade.
二年級開始
So he was a little old for you?
所以他對於你來說年齡有點大了
I keep telling him that.
我一直這樣跟他講
He never listens.
可他從來聽不進去
He never do? - No.
他從來聽不進去? -對啊
What is your dig?
你主要幹什麼?
I must have done them all.
我肯定我做了太多了
Monsters under the bed, a cheerleader,
床下惡魔 啦啦隊長
governor...
執行者...
These days have not been the right time to tell him the truth.
這些天不是告訴他真相的好時機
And you?
你呢?
I'm crazy in love with her.
我瘋狂地愛著她
- oh! tough one. - Yeah.
噢 不容易啊  - 是啊
It's been hurry.
真快
I think She's almost done with me.
我想她快要跟我說再見了
Good, Great,  Run away while you can.
好 太好了 能跑就跑
Tell her to open the door and you run.
告訴她開門 你走
You don't want to end up like me.
你不想像我這樣吧
I guess not.
不想
- Captain Excellent. - Christopher.
- 萬能上校 - 克斯特佛
Nice to meet you.
很高興見到你
See you around.
再見
Oh!
噢
What?
幹嗎
What? What?
幹嗎 幹嗎
Wait a second.
停一下
Son of bitch!
混蛋!
Do not react here.
不要這樣
Do not tell me how to react.
別告訴我該怎樣
- It's not like that. - Shut up.
-不像你想的那樣 -閉嘴
What? What is this? Richard
什麼? 這是怎麼回事? 理查德
Who is that? Who the fuck is that?
她是誰? 操她媽到底是誰?
She is the babysitter.
她是保姆
Get out. Get out.
出去 出去
Get out!
出去!
Hi, Lucy! Hi, Peter!
你好 露絲 你好 彼得
Hi
你好
Claire we'll just be ...
克萊爾 我們去...
I did not sleep with the babysitter, if that's what you think of.
如果你在想我是不是跟保姆睡了 我沒有
Oh, that is so comforting.
哦? 你可真會安慰人
Why do we even have a babysitter?
我們為什麼要雇保姆呢?
It was just a kegger, Claire. That was all.
是個啤酒聚會  克萊爾 就這樣
just a kegger?
只是個聚會
And with whom exactly did you have a kegger?
那麼你到底跟誰一起開聚會呢?
just kids from high school .
就是些上高中的孩子
Richard, just stop.
理查德 不要說了
none of this is ok. -ok
這些都不對勁兒 - 好吧
You knew we were coming this weekend.
你知道這個週末我們要來
Why are you doing this?
你為什麼要這麼做?
I've been a bit at a loss.
我有點迷茫
what a bullshit answer.
真是個爛借口
I was being flandering and Abby was being ...
我很孤獨 艾比很...
What? Abby was being what?
什麼? 艾比怎樣?
A friend.
友善 像個朋友
For God's sake, that is not a friend, that's a child.
天哪 她不是朋友 她是個孩子
- You do have friends. - No, I do not.
你有朋友  -我沒有
I think that is a touble here...
我覺得有麻煩了
Cause you do not have a relate to other human beings.
因為你跟其它人都沒有聯繫
Yeah, you isolate yourself.
對 你把自己同其他人隔離開了
Oh, you can talk.
哦 你可以這樣說
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
你這該死的話什麼意思?
You can be cold, Claire.
原來你可以這麼殘忍 克萊爾
I think we just get out of here.
我想我們得走了
We just get out of here
我想我們得離開這兒
leave this area.
趕緊離開
- Where? - I do not know, anywhere.
-去哪? - 我不知道 除隨便
I don't know if it's your profession or what... you know, but it makes your heart.
我不知道是不是你的職業 讓你變得冷酷
I cannot and I don't accept that.
我接受不了
I wanna to have a baby
我想要個孩子
Is that what this is all about?
就這樣而已?
We could have a baby, Claire.
我們可以有個孩子的 克萊爾
Why did not we have a baby? Why?
為什麼我們沒要個孩子呢 為什麼?
Because you're a baby.
因為你自己就是個孩子
You're an enfant.
你真沒用
You still have an imaginary friend.
就算到現在你還有個假想的朋友
I just wanted a little warm thing.
我只是想要一個 一開始就可以跟它在一起的
Something simple  I could start with.
小小的 溫暖的 單純的東西
A simple relationship with a person that was new and pure.
跟某個人建立一種新的 純潔的關係
well, I could be me, they could be them.
我可以做自己 他們可以做他們
and that's all I've expected we can build.
這就是我想我們能創造的東西
In this world there's someone other than me
在這個世界上 除我之外還有
to think about and be about.
我可以想念 可以想成為的人
and the relief of being able to give the world to someone else
有一種能夠分享世界給其他人的寬慰感
and let it be there and let them have their turn.
讓他們也能這麼做
so it doesn't end with me.
所有的一切不會因為我的死而終結
Well that's all you, Where do I come in?
那這是你所想的 那我呢?
What do you mean?
什麼意思?
God, you're the mother.
天啊 你是他們的媽媽啊
Ah, I am so sorry, guys.
呃 夥計們 我們非常抱歉
We are gonna go we're just gonna go...
我們要走了 我們就是要走了
We can be just anywhere Anywhere.
我可以去哪都行的
I'm so sorry.- No no no. All right.
真抱歉 -沒事兒 我們出去就行了
We're just going out  -I will walk you out I'm sorry
我送你們 對不起
Wish you all go on a crew or something
你們一起出去一下吧
Okay.
好吧
Okay. Take care.
保重
Alright. if we are gonna do this, let's ...
好吧 如果我們要這樣吵的話 我們...
Alright, by the way, what's she like? like 13,14?
順便問一下 她多大了 十三歲? 十四歲?
At least we'll get the fact straight.
至少先解決問題
It was you, Richard. you didn't want to have a baby.
是你 理查德 是你不想要孩子
you weren't ready.
你沒準備好
so that little fuzzy fucking speech my friends had to hear was bull shit.
你當著我朋友面講的溫情兮兮的話純粹是扯淡
now, I know that I'm...  I can't.
我知道我...我講不出來
so I guess I am the bad guy.
我想是我不好
No not the novel that's...
別碰小說
I'd rather you didn't...
我寧願你...
What is this? What is this?
這是什麼? 這是什麼?
That's it.
就是我的創作
After all this time out here and this is it?
呆了這麼長時間 就寫了這些?
this is That?
就這些?
Maybe you should spent more time working instead of ...
或許下次你該忙一下工作
fucking the babysitter.
而不是和小保姆做
- No. I. .. - You're useless.  -Yes
-不是 我...-你沒用  -對
- You are totally useless! - Yes. I am.
-你徹底沒用! -是 我沒用
What is wrong with you?
你到底怎麼回事?
I do not know what to do with my hands.
我不知道我這雙手能幹什麼
Everyone.
所有人
Janeth, my sister and Olive all have been made
珍妮斯 我姐姐和奧利夫都覺得
I have the one who made me laugh.
我有一個讓我開心的人
What happened?
是怎麼回事?
I do not know what happened.
我不知道是怎麼回事
You stopped laughing.
你不再笑了
- May I help you? - Yeah.
-要幫忙嗎? -嗯
I came here to pay my respects.
我來這悼念
- sorry? - Heath Hen, the North American Heath Hen...
什麼? -黑琴雞 北美黑琴雞...
it's where the last one lived and died.
這就是最後一隻生活和死亡的地方
I don't know anything about the Heath Hen.
我對黑琴雞一無所知
But you are welcome to look around.
但是歡迎你到處逛逛
We've got several varieties of proper.
我們有好幾個品種
Thank you.
謝謝
So that is what the end of something looks like.
這麼說這就是結束
The world went on, Richard.
地球依然在轉 理查德
But never the same.
但是不會一樣了
We do not know how much it changes things.
雖然我們不知道究竟改變了多少
but it is just being here.
但是終究是改變了
The ripple of the fact.
事實的餘波
if the chicken hadn't died out here,
如果這裡的雞沒有滅絕
you will be perfectly adusted.
或許你就跟其它人一樣了
Maybe.
或許
Doubtful.
我真懷疑
Instead of a child, I am a loser
我不是小孩 是個失敗者
and I am condemned to believe in Captain.
注定了要相信上校
it's like a little hand.
像個小手
It's ...It's time for you to go.
你...你該離開了
No.
不
You know what I am saying, Captain.
你知道我的意思 上校
I mean, go and never come back.
我是說 走吧 再別回來了
I'm not ready.
我還不放心
it doesn't matter.
不重要了
You can not help me anymore.
你再也不能幫我了
The doctor is right.
醫生是對的
but You will be alone.
但是你會孤單
Yes
是
as the last of my kind.
我是最後一個
OK.
好吧
do the voice.
喊口號吧
One last time.
喊最後一次
Please.
求你了
When the world is peril.
當世界面臨危險
When evil surrounds you.
當惡魔在你身邊
When danger is lurking.
當危險潛伏而至
Who do you call?
你會叫誰?
Captain Excellent!
優秀上校!
I wish I had a really amazing and vital father like him.
我希望我有一個像他棒的好父親
Captain?
上校?
Richmond regarded his solitude... The ...
理查漫 孤芳...
Merton regarded his solitude ... Norton regarded his solitude ...
莫頓孤芳 諾頓孤芳
Horton regarded his solitude ...Norton thought ...
霍頓孤芳...  諾頓想...
Norwood regarded his solitude...The ...
諾伍德孤芳
Richard? Richard?
理查德? 理查德?
Richard!
理查德!
Richard regarded his solitude as something sacred.
理查德 孤芳自賞
I had dreams last night and uh. ..
我昨晚夢見. ..
you were in it.
夢見了你
ah? was it interesting?
嗯? 是有趣的事兒嗎?
you were you.
你還是你
You're leaving, aren't you?
你要走了,是嗎?
yeah, you know, because of the
是啊 你知道 是因為
- situation ...
這種局面
- Yeah.
是的
I figured it.
我知道
You know, spring is ...
你知道嗎 春天
my favorite time.
是我最喜歡的季節
cause summer has not arrived yet.
因為夏天還沒到
and it's not fucking cold.
而且不會那麼要命的寒冷
uh ... I. ..
呃  我
I made something for you.
我有東西送你
It is the swan.
是天鵝
The beautiful and graceful swan.
美麗優雅的天鵝
It's ...Richard, it's perfect.
它  理查德 它太美了
yeah
嗯
Thank you.
謝謝你
It seems like that we were just come started.
感覺好像我們剛剛認識那會兒
Take care.
保重
Okay.
好
okay
就這樣吧
I am a horse's ass.
我是個混蛋
Yes, you are.
對 你就是
I am sorry.
對不起
I kind of need some help to get this couch in.
我需要幫手把沙發重放回屋裡
Richard regarded his solitude as something sacred.
理查德孤芳自賞 把它看做神聖
As well as a badge of honor.
和光榮的勳章
A clock to be warned of warm to life
是提醒我們要讓生活溫暖
As well as safety.
和安全的警鐘
Solitude is who he was.
他整個人都是孤獨的
This cast those into his lives to make him feel barely content.
孤獨影響了他的生活,使他對生活不滿意
Richard was certain that there was not lined.
理查德知道沒有人像他一樣
It was just hard on man.
這對於一個人來說簡直太難受了
maybe it was because
他之所以沒有所得可能是因為
he gave nothing and he received nothing in return.
他沒有付出 也沒有收穫
In any case, the situation became untolerable.
不管如何 這種境況都讓人無法忍受
the closed things he had as his friends were either imaginary or extinct.
那些他視作朋友的東西不是虛幻的就是滅絕了
Richard had reached a point in his life
理查德瞭解他自己的生活
but it was no longer enough.
但是不夠深入
And then he met a girl.
後來他遇到了個女孩
And she was warm.
她讓人感覺很溫暖
And she was sad.
但是她很憂傷
And she was maybe lonely in a way that reminded him of himself.
或許她還很孤單 這多少讓他想到了他自己
She lost things that no girl had lost.
她失去了別的女孩兒不該失去的東西
And she knew things.
她也知道一些她們不曾知道的事情
And she taught him.
她把這些教給他
And Richard thought maybe that was what friendship feels like.
理查德覺得或許這就是所謂的友誼吧
Maybe.
可能
It was just in the blinks.
它轉瞬即逝
it barely began really.
實際上它還算不上開始
But in those long few winter days.
但是在那漫長的冬天裡
She gave him so much.
她已給他很多了
Enough so that Richard could go on.
多到理查德可以由此獲得新生
And what did he give her?
那麼他又給了她什麼呢?
Just a few words on a page.
只是一頁寫了字的紙
Not much, perhaps.
或許不多
But for Abby.
但是對於艾比
He hoped that was enough.
他希望這就夠了
Okay.
嗯